http://animetranscripts.wikispaces.com
I said if you won't save me
It's all that I've ever known...
Callin' out to all
If you know what I mean...
It's all that I've ever known
Please don't waste my time
Here am I, lost and found...
A dying scream makes no sound
Callin' out to all that I've ever known
Calling him up in-and-out of nowhere
We live a dying dream...
I tried to talk with God to no avail
Catch the wheel that breaks a butterfly
Cry the rain that fills the ocean wide
スラム化しちゃってるね
This place has become a slum.
けど、まだマンションにも人はいるみたいだ
But it seems that there are still people living in the apartments.
Could it be that your home is one of those apartments?
滝沢くんちもマンションかな
I wonder.
どうかなぁ… 住所からすると一戸建て？
んなわけないか
Judging from the address, it seems to be a complete building—As if.
EPISODE 3
EVENING AT THE LATE SHOW
あの辺だ
It's somewhere over there.
The center of the explosion is that way.
爆心地はあっちだから、家は残ってるね
Your house should still be around.
Yeah...
But people probably don't live in any of those buildings over there.
でもさ、あの辺に人が住んでそうな建物って
Let's just take a look for now.
とにかく行ってみよう！
ここだ
This is the place.
You're sure that it's here... right?
本当にここ…だよね
住所的には…
It should be, based on the address...
開いた…
It opened.
どっかに電源があるはずだ
There should be a light switch somewhere in here.
けど、こんなところに普通、住むかな
But really, nobody would actually live in a place like this, right?
True.
だよな
何か思い出さない？
Do you remember anything?
さっきも鍵、無意識に…
You took out your keys unconsciously just now.
う～ん、感覚はあるんだけど
Well, I feel something, but...
滝沢くん！
Takizawa-kun!
What's this?
何だ？
That surprised me.
びっくりした…
What are you doing here?
お前、なんでこんなところにいるの？
What's wrong?
なんだよ！
This is definitely your home.
ここ、きっと滝沢くんちだよ
After all, he seems to recognize you.
だって、その子、滝沢君のことよく知ってるみたいだもん
Yeah.
確かに、こいつは俺のことを知ってるみたいだ
It looks like he does.
無理言って悪かったな。所轄、違うのに
I apologize for asking something unreasonable.
This isn't under my jurisdiction.
It's part of my job after all.
これも仕事ですから
じゃあ、悪いが一時間ほど待っててくれ
Sorry to trouble you, but wait an hour for me.
それで戻らなかったら、勝手に帰ってくれていいよ
Feel free to leave if I'm not back by then.
あの兄ちゃん、本当にこんなところに住んでんのか？
That kid... Does he really live here?
確かに、ここを丸ごと買い取った履歴はあるが…
Well, there are logs which indicate that he bought the whole building.
記憶を消したいのはお前だけじゃねえ
You're not the only one who wants to erase their memory.
やっぱりいてもらわなきゃ困るぜ
I guess this will keep bothering me unless I go in.
It looks like there's a way up.
上には行けるみたいだ
Isn't this amazing?
すごくない？
ショッピングモールが自宅って
You have a shopping mall for a home.
にしても、こんなとこ住んでるってさ…どうなの？
It's weird that I'm staying somewhere like this, right?
これじゃ「ドーン・オブ・ザ・デッド」でしょ？
Is this like Dawn of the Dead?
それも映画？
Is that a movie?
Yeah.
うん
でも、ちゃんと調べてみたら何か見つかるよ
But we might discover something if we dig through this place thoroughly.
Newspapers are still being delivered here and we might find stuff like mail or this place's register book.
新聞も配達されてたし
郵便物とかここの登記簿とかも…
Takizawa
Akira!
We're gonna kill you!
Is this for real?!
マジかよ！ ここってあの写真の場所じゃ！
Isn't this where that photo was taken?
We're gonna kill you!
Takizawa
Akira!
This somehow seems to be Takizawa Akira's home...
どうやらここは滝沢朗の家らしいけど
俺はここで何やってたんだ？
What was I doing here?
Takizawa-kun! What's wrong?
滝沢くん！どうしたの！
Have you found something?
何かあったの？
いや、なんもないよ！
No, there's nothing!
ここ、シネコンだ
This is a movie theater.
レイトショーにでも招待するつもりか
Do you want me to invite you to a late show?
Is that your home?
そこがお前のウチなのか？
What is this place?
何、ここ？
What an awesome room!
相当いい部屋じゃない！
やっぱりここ、滝沢くんちだよ
This must be your home!
そうなのかな
You think so?
Definitely!
絶対そうだよ
Look, your memories of movies are very vivid, right?
ほら、滝沢くん、映画のことはすっごく覚えてたじゃない？
それってきっとここの支配人かなんかだったからだよ
It's probably because you're the manager of this place or something.
Manager?
支配人ね
爆心地、ここからも見える
You can see the center of the explosion from here.
You're right...
本当だ
Oh, that's right!
あっ、そうだ！
君、なんか好きな映画ある？
何でもリクエストしてよ
Are there any movies you like?
Feel free to request any movie you want.
たぶん、上映できるから
I'll probably be able to show it.
映画、あんまり見ないからよく知らないし
I don't really watch a lot of movies, so I don't really know much about them...
At least one should come to mind, right?
一つくらい思い浮かぶでしょ？
For example, the movie you watched on your first date.
初めてのデートで見た映画とかさ
えっとじゃあ…
Um... then...
That French movie with a dolphin and a diver.
あのイルカとダイバーが出てくるフランス映画
Oh, that one?
お〜、あれか
Even though you can't remember anything about yourself?
自分のことは何も覚えてないくせに？
That's right.
そうだね
でも、またなんでその映画なの？
But why did you choose that movie?
It's the favorite movie of someone I've always liked.
ずっと好きだった人が
好きだった映画だったから
Hey Juiz, I have a request.
ねえジュイズ、お願いがあるんだけど
今すぐ見たい映画があるんだ
There's a movie I want to see immediately.
うん、今は豊洲のシネコン
Yes.
I'm in a movie theater in Toyosu.
警察？
Police?
Okay.
はい
I'm checking through the list of movies that were delivered there previously.
それでは、そちらに以前搬入されている映画を調べますので
Please wait for a while.
しばらくお待ちください
ノブレス・オブリージュ。今夜も救世主たらんことを
Noblesse Oblige.
Please continue your work as a Savior.
I wonder.
どうかな。せめて紳士ではいたいよね
I want to become a gentleman at least.
なんなんだ？ ここは
What happened here?
A refugee camp?
難民の収容所かっつーの
それに、この携帯の山
And this mountain of cellphones...
I see, that kid was...
そうか、あの兄ちゃん…
Don't think you'll
get away with this!
ニートのガキどもが失踪している事件に絡んでんのか
Could he have something to do with those missing NEETs?
Is it possible that a Selecao was behind both the missile attacks and this incident too?
ミサイル攻撃といい、あの事件も犯人はセレソンか
金使うだけじゃなく、真面目に履歴チェックしたら
If I had actually checked through the logs instead of just spending money,
今頃大手柄だったのにな
I might have already cracked a major case.
Well, even though this is none of my business, since I intend to start my life anew with eight billion...
まあ、新たに80億手に入れて
人生やり直す俺には
もはや関係ねえ話だが
Oh yeah.
そうだ。上映前には携帯切っとかなきゃね
I've got to switch my phone off before the movie starts.
The number you dialed is currently out of service area.
おかけになった番号は電波が届かない場所にいるか
電源が入っていないため、かかりません
Therefore, we cannot reach the person you have called.
Hats off to your efforts, Oosugi.
しかし、大杉の努力にも頭が下がる
It's just pointless struggling.
無駄なあがきだと思うけど
Saki
「今日、みっちょん所に泊まったことにして
Micchan, pretend that I stayed over at your place.
That's what I told my sister, Asako.
お願い。朝子姉さんにはそう言ってあるから」
When did you receive this mail?!
って、このメールいつ！？
Around 11 P.M.
十一時ぐらいかな
何？
What happened?
大杉、帰るぞ
Oosugi, let's head home.
どこに泊まるのやら
I wonder where she's staying.
The Cold Blue
俺やっぱ、ここの映写技師だったんじゃねえ？
I guess I'm a projectionist here?
Feels like Cinema Paradiso.
「ニュー・シネマ・パラダイス」的な
Amazing!
すごい！ 大きいスクリーン
Such a big screen!
In here?
ここか
あいつ、どこだ
Where is he?
ふん、あそこか
Over there?
刑事さん、一人っすか？
Mr. Policeman, are you here alone?
ってことは俺を逮捕しに来たわけでもない
That means that you aren't here to arrest me.
You noticed me?
気づいてたのか
Yeah. Sort of.
ええ、まあ
You came to see me for personal reasons, right?
俺に個人的に会いに来たってことですかね
もしかしてと思ってたんだけど、助かっちった
I thought so.  Guess I'm in luck.
そうか
I see. You looked at my logs?
こっちの履歴、調べやがったのか
履歴ってこれのことっすかね
By logs, are you referring to this?
Just what is Selecao?
あと、「セレソン」って何っすか？
実は俺、記憶喪失ってやつで
To tell you the truth, I've lost my memories, so I don't recall anything.
これが何なのか全然覚えてないんすよ
だから、おっさんに色々聞きたいなと思って
That's why I've got a lot of questions for you, old man.
お前、本当に記憶消したのか
You really erased your memories?
どうしたのかな、滝沢くん
I wonder what Takizawa-kun is doing.
なるほど！
I see.
The brainwashing program at Harima Laboratory was actually used to erase your memories.
播磨研究所の洗脳プログラムってのは
本当に記憶を消せるんだな
I'll use that too one day.
いつか俺も使わせてもらうよ
However, I've got to snatch that away from you first.
だが、まずはお前のそいつを頂かなきゃな
You were careless, kid.
迂闊したな、兄ちゃん
何なの、その携帯…
What's with that cellphone?
おっさんのには…いくら入ってた
Old man, how much was yours charged with?
You're quite stubborn.
しぶてえな
I'll take the remaining money in this.
こいつの残金は俺がもらう
Initially, you and I both had ten billion.
俺もお前も最初は１００億持ってたはずだ
けどな、たった１００億で
腐り切ったこの国を救うことなんざできっこねえんだよ
However, ten billion alone isn't enough to save this corrupted country.
くだらねえゲームに人を巻き込みやがって！
We were dragged into a pointless game!
やっぱ、刑事って強えや…
The police really are strong.
Old man, she has nothing to do with this...
おっさん、あの子は…さ、関係…ないから
It takes money to kill someone.
殺しは金がかかるからな。
無駄なことはやらねえよ
I won't do anything pointless.
そうだ、一つだけ教えてやる
Oh right, I'll tell you just one thing.
このノブレス携帯な、残高がゼロになると
A Supporter will come and kill the owner of this Noblesse cellphone once the money on it is depleted.
サポーターってのが持ち主を殺しにくるそうだ
This is one of the rules.
そういうルールなんだ
It's a pity, but you'll die even if she's saved.
残念だったな、兄ちゃん
あの子が助かってもお前は死ぬ
Now we're even, old man.
これでお相子だ
おっさん
サポーターって何だ？ また謎だよ…
Who is this Supporter?
Another mystery...
ごめん
Sorry. I wasn't able to join you for the late show.
レイトショーには行かれそうにねえや
お前…
You...
Do you know where Takizawa-kun went?
滝沢くんがどこに行ったか知ってる？
He should have just told me if he didn't want to be with me.
一緒にいたくないなら
そう言ってくれればいいのにね
Ouch...
痛え…
ナイス・メッセージ
Nice message.
Stupid Takizawa
Shall we return this?
さて、こいつを返しに行ってくるか
「一生遊べる金を手に入れた。
"Got enough money to play with for the rest of my life.
I rented a car for you, so come up to Kabukicho."
ハイヤー呼んだから歌舞伎町まで来い」と
ATO Taxi Hire Service
Kill these 3
in front of me
[Details]
Entertainment
Balance:
Selecao Activity Log
Update
History
Delete
Switch
Display
Function
奇麗に使い切ったぜ
I've used it all up.
Since they're the same type of phone they should work in the same way.
機種が同じなら操作も同じだろ、普通
Damn. Guess I'll ask Juiz.
くそっ、ジュイスに聞いてみっか
はい、ジュイスです
This is Juiz.
Ah, there's something I want to ask you.
ああ、一つ聞きたいことがあるんだ
もしもこいつを他人に拾われたらどうなる？
What will happen if someone else picks up this phone?
Can anyone use it?
誰でも使えるのか？
指紋認証がありますので他者には絶対使用できませんが
Fingerprint recognition is required, so no one else is able to use it.
Is there a problem?
何か問題でも？
ああ、そりゃ安全だ。そう、じゃあな
Ah, that's quite safe then.
Well, bye.
ちゃんちゃんっと…
Completely safe...
Why am I always making these kinds of mistakes?
どうしていつも俺はこうドジなんだ
Public
Phone
Saki
Me
君のおかげだ
It's all thanks to you.
早く出ろよ、おっさん
Old man, hurry up and answer.
いるんだろ？ おっさん
Old man, you're there, right?
ねえ、近藤刑事さん
Hello, Mr. Kondou, the policeman.
せっかく大事な手帳を届けてあげようとしてんだからさ
And here I was, planning to return your precious badge to you.
At least answer the phone.
電話くらい出なよ
てめえ、どうやって…
How the heck did you get it?
You finally answered.
やっと出た。おっさん、今どこにいんの？
Old man, where are you right now?
I'm right in the center of Kabukicho.
歌舞伎町のど真ん中だ。貴様、今すぐすっ飛んで来い！
Come here immediately!
歌舞伎町ね… で、そこどうやって行くんだっけ？
Kabukicho?
How do I get there?
Are you making fun of me?
てめえ、ナメてんのか
Well... I have no memories.
いや、だから… 俺、記憶ないしさ
Head towards Kiba on the Metropolitan Expressway...
木場方面に抜けて首都高ね
Kabuki-cho   First Avenue
ミサエ…
Misae...
Why... are you here?
どうしてお前がここに？
一生遊んで暮らせるお金って何？
What did you mean by "Got enough money to play with for the rest of my life?"
どうしてそれを…
How did you know that?
愛人へのメールを妻に送ってどうするの？
What would you do if you sent a message to your wife instead of your mistress?
This is the end.
これでお終い…
What happened, old man?
どうした？ おっさん
Shut up, kid.
うるせえんだよ、兄ちゃん
今、救急車呼んでやるよ
I'll call for an ambulance now.
Don't do anything unnecessary.
余計なことをすんな。
どうやら俺はお終いらしい
This seems to be the end for me, no matter what you do.
勝手に死ぬなよ
Don't die on me!
まだ聞きたいことが…
I still have questions to ask—
I don't care.
知るか？
There are ten other Selecao like us with these cellphones.
俺たちの他にあと１０人
同じ携帯を持ったセレソンがいるはずだ
"Selecao" refers to the players who are forced into playing this crappy game.
セレソンってのは
このくそゲームに強制的に参加させられたプレイヤーのことだ
You're able to access the logs with your cellphone as well, right?
お前の携帯にも履歴が届くだろ
Find the other Selecaos using those logs and ask them.
後はその履歴たどって他のセレソン探してそいつに聞け
"Who am I" or something.
「僕って誰ですか」ってな
That is, if anyone is willing to meet a dangerous Selecao like you.
ただし、お前みたいな危ないセレソンに
会ってくれる奴がいればの話だがな
Dangerous Selecao?
危ないセレソン？
You gathered twenty thousand NEETs at the center of the explosion and killed them.
お前、二万人のニート
爆心地に集めて殺そうとしたろ
Wait, is it you... or the Supporter?
待てよ、お前、それともサポーターか？
そういうことか。だからミサエが…
I see.
That's why Misae...
何言ってんだかさっぱり分かんねえよ
What are you saying? I don't understand at all!
I was tricked.
やられたよ。こいつを持って消えろ
Take this and leave.
Hurry up and leave!
早く消えろ！
俺の負けだ
I lost.
俺だって最初は正義をなそうとしてたのに…
At first, I did it for justice...
夜は封印
戸惑い混じれば終わる
迷い出すぐらいならいっそ
わ     け
理由も捨てよう
また夢に溺れる
不確かに続いてく未来
まだ君を許せる
意味を知れる
耳を澄ますための夜
その理由を真似て変われる
君の呼吸を知るために
未来の根を切っても構わない